"The Stranger I Met" Episode 3
《我遇见的陌生人》 第3集
(Wu Gang Dumu)
（吴刚杜姆）
(Kyung Gi Joo)
（京基珠）
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》
So this is not an ordinary car but a time travel machine.
所以这不是一辆普通的汽车而是 一台时光旅行机器
Time travel is over there
时光旅行在那一边
I was hit by this car
我被这车撞了
This goes back to 1987 ?
这要追溯到1987年 ？
- Cool - Cool, right?
- 酷 - 酷，对吧？
Seeing such a situation, can you still say such a thing?
看到这样的情况， 你还能说出这样的话吗？
The car will be repaired anyway
无论如何车都会修好的
Until then, stay here
在那之前，请留在这里
My name is Li Shengyi
我叫李升伊
don't call me mom
别叫我妈妈
really scared
真的很害怕
What's your real name?
真名是什么？
My name is Baisu
我叫巴伊苏
Are they all girls from your school?
都是你们学校的女生吗？
He fell into the water without saving him
没有救他掉进水里
Which friends are watching?
哪些朋友在旁边观看？
Pretend you don't want to see it, sister
假装你不想看到，姐姐
one year later
一年后
I will die at the age of 35
我将在35岁那年死去
The defendant who killed me was in 1987
杀了我的被告是在1987年
Because Wu Zongri is the culprit of the serial murders
因为吴宗日是连环杀人案的罪魁祸首
This also appeared at the scene of my death
这也出现在我死亡的现场
This is the defendant's trademark from 1987
这是1987年 被告的商标
In any case, it must be sent back before
无论如何，必须在此之前寄回
(Bom Bom Theater)
（Bom Bom 剧场）
that's why
这就是为什么
(Part 3 - The Secret You Have)
（第 3 部分 - 你拥有的秘密）
I know
我知道
The era suddenly comes and there is something to do
突然到来的时代 有事可做
How illogical and strange
多么不合逻辑和 奇怪
but
但
go out
出去
Because it's colder here than outside
因为这里比外面冷
First let's go outside
首先我们到外面去
Part (3)
第(3)部分
Anyway, I think it will be difficult to go back tonight.
反正我觉得今晚就很难回去了
Get dressed and come out
穿好衣服出来
Are Kimizu and our mother friends?
基米祖和我们的妈妈是朋友吗？
same class
同一个班级
Novel How did it actually happen?
小说 实际上是如何发生的？
Because no one likes me very much
因为大家都不太喜欢我
that's why
这就是为什么
That's why I want to say...
这就是为什么我想说..
I want to die
我想死
Mom will have times like this too
妈妈也会有这样的时光
never imagined
从未想象过
Is that all?
仅仅是这样吗？
The mother time I didn’t know
我不知道的母亲时光
I once wanted to be a novelist
我曾经 想成为一名小说家
What kind of content?
什么样的内容？
Can you give my mother a signed book?
你能给我妈妈一本签名书吗？
Do not you understand?
你看不懂吗？
What books will I read?
我会读什么书？
At the same time, how much do I miss my mom?
与此同时，我有多少想念妈妈的时光？
No
不
Everything can change here
这里一切都可以改变
(Bom Bom Theater)
（Bom Bom 剧场）
How did you know?
你是怎么知道的？
I think I can't go back now
我想我现在回不去了
There's work to be done here
这里还有工作要做
What to do there?
那里该怎么办？
(Bom Bom Theater)
（Bom Bom 剧场）
Do you remember them?
你还记得他们吗？
5 months and 14 days, 5 months and 16 days, 1987
5个月14天、5个月16天，1987年
Two women take turns to die
两个女人轮流死去
Then No. 20 disappeared and has not been found yet.
然后20号就消失了， 至今还没找到
a woman
一个女人
Yes, I've seen them all around
是的，我在附近都见过他们
Knowledge
知识
Those who were not killed by you
那些没有被你杀掉的人
not really
并不真地
If those detectives hadn't blamed me then...
如果那些侦探 当时没有责备我的话..
I am strong
我很强
Please trust me
请相信我
Then this
那么这个
List of main suspects at the time
当时主要嫌疑人名单
There are three people including you
包括你在内共有三个人
Do you remember the other two?
你还记得另外两个人吗？
Yes, because the community is small
是的，因为小区很小
from now on
今后
Regarding these six people, including the parties concerned
关于这六人，包括当事人在内
tell me everything you remember
告诉我你记得的一切
Just small is fine
小的就好
I don't know if it's accurate because it has a long memory
我不知道它是否准确，因为它的记忆很长
Just for reference, don’t worry
仅供参考，不用担心
I will introduce it in detail myself
我会亲自详细介绍
Because this is a case that doesn't leave much evidence
因为这是一个没有留下太多证据的案件
That's why it's as close as possible
这就是为什么它尽可能接近
I will join them and watch
我会加入他们并观看
Every action is monitored
每个行为都会受到监控
you have to wait
你必须等待
Until shortly before the incident
直到事发前不久
At that time, at least half of these six people were of mixed race.
当时，这六人至少有一半 是混血的
Where do you think it is?
你认为它在哪里？
I'm mixed raceI'm mixed race
我是混血我是混血
School?
学校？
School
学校
start from there
从那里开始
I think I have to go to school
我想我必须进入学校
I have to go to school
我得去学校了
hot pot
火锅
- Hot hot hot - Are you crazy?
- 热热热 - 你疯了吗？
It's hot
很热
(Contact to inquire about spies and communist criminals)
（联系询问间谍和共产主义罪犯）
Do I really have to pay if I get caught?
如果被抓到真的要付钱吗？
Is it because of meeting a stranger that this happened?
到底是因为遇到了陌生的人，才这样的呢？
Everyone I see is weird
我看到的每个人都很奇怪
look at him
看着他
- Let's go - Next round
- 走吧 - 下一轮
- Kyung Hee - Miss
- 庆熙 - 小姐
I even know how many hammers and spoons he has in his house
我什至知道他家里有多少锤子和勺子
he is hopeless
他是无望的
Do you recognize an unfamiliar face or unfamiliar words?
你是否认识一张陌生的面孔、 陌生的话语？
Like coming from a strange other world
就像来自一个陌生的另一个世界
Strange faces, another world
陌生的面孔，另一个世界
Yes, and where is this place?
是的，而且这个地方在哪里？
People who don’t know what day of the week it is
不知道今天是星期几的人
- Yeah, I don't know - Well
- 是的，我不知道 - 嗯
and then
进而
Holding a strange machine and saying strange things
拿着奇怪的机器， 说奇怪的话
Weird machine...
奇怪的机器..
Yesterday I met such a person
昨天我遇到了这样一个人
Oh, great, I get to see you every day
噢，太好了，我 每天都会见到你
I can see clearly because I have good eyes
我看得很清楚， 因为我的眼睛很好
No
不
Who is that?
那是谁？
Who are you asking?
你在问谁？
School, do you think this makes sense now?
学校，你现在认为这有意义吗？
as a student, not a teacher
作为 一名学生，而不是老师
Is there such a terrible thing?
有这么可怕的事情吗？
I don't even know how hot it is
我什至不知道有多热
Well, you'll know when you look at it
好吧，你看看就会知道
if you remove makeup
如果你卸妆
Because the face of the modern era is difficult to predict
因为现时代的面貌难以预测
If you say you have been out of school for three years
如果你说你已经失学三年了
completely..
完全..
You don't have to worry about this
你不必担心这个
Have you forgotten where this place is?
你忘记这个地方在哪里了吗？
Drink slowly while it's hot
趁热慢慢喝
I will never forget 1987
我不会忘记1987年
Anyway, I can't go back now
无论如何，我此刻 无法回去
It is safe to take a form
采取一种形式是安全的
I did it over there, so I can do it too, right?
我那边做了，所以 我也可以做，对吧？
on the other hand
另一方面
Don't you think this plan is wrong?
你不觉得这个计划是错误的吗？
What procedures are required? After both parties apply
需要什么程序？ 双方申请后
Not that one
不是那个
Is that why we have to do it here ?
这就是我们必须在这里做的原因吗 ？
So I think it's only right to first explain what it's all about
所以 我认为首先解释一下它的全部内容是正确的
Is anyone coming this time?
这次有人来吗？
Is it possible to do this?
是否有可能做到这一点？
After all, he is a teacher from Wuzheng Middle School
好歹是五正中学的 老师
If the chairman knew
如果主席知道的话
We are also familiar with the battalion commander
营长我们 也很熟悉
What are Badang Badan doing here?
巴东八探来这里做什么？
I'll be back soon
我一会儿就回来
What happened this time
这次怎么了
Wujiang Municipal Public Security Bureau Serious Case Brigade
吴江市公安局重案大队
Badong Detective No. 8
巴东侦探八号
I'm here to confirm. please wait for a moment
我是来确认的。 请稍等一下
stay
停留
I think it needs to be explained what the problem is
我认为需要解释问题是什么
Do you think it is necessary now?
您认为现在有必要吗？
here
这里
teacher
老师
Will you call the chairman?
你会打电话给主席吗？
That guy is always talking nonsense on a moonlit night
月夜那家伙总是 胡言乱语
Mazuto
真烦人
Let's register
我们来注册吧
Carefully this time
这次仔细
- Shin - Didn't you hear?
- 申 - 你没听到吗？
I'm here because I got a complaint about a stranger
我来是因为我收到关于陌生人的投诉
Register
登记
Disappeared once before
之前消失过一次
If you don't even make that much effort
如果你连那么多努力都没有
I don't think there's any other way to prove who you are
我认为没有其他方法可以证明你是谁
I know
我知道
let's go
我们走吧
Wait, police station?
等等，警察局？
- Come on - Police station?
- 来吧 - 警察局？
-Wait a moment
- 等一下
Are you crazy?
你疯了？
Are you doing this because you trust the chairman?
你这样做是因为信任主席吗？
to show action
来展示行动
I know you are so passionate
我知道你如此热情
I helped because I was worried that I would suffer in vain.
我帮忙是因为我担心我会白白受苦
this is a waste of time
这是浪费时间
Have accurate information and a way to prove it
有准确的信息和 证明它的方法
You can verify it yourself if you wish
如果您愿意，可以自行验证
Have specific information
有具体信息
Yes
是的
This kid...
这孩子..
Wuzheng Middle School senior students
五征中学 高年级学生
Ross
罗斯
-Is it really big? -certainly
-真的很大吗？ -当然
OK
好的
-Hi
- 嗨
oh
哦
What year were you born? Aw 1965
你出生于哪一年？Aw 1965
May 15, 1965
1965年5月15日
Good morning sir
你好先生
Well, hello, Miss Sun
嗯，你好，孙小姐
- Hello - Mitsu?
- 你好 - 美津？
- I'm a lady - Cool, yes.
- 我是女士 - 酷，是的
I'm really grateful for this
对此，我真的非常感激
What should I do after my registration number is 63?
我的注册号 63 之后怎么办？
I will take a short break
我会短暂休息
come over
过来
Why ?
为什么 ？
- Come here, wait a minute. - What is this place?
- 过来，等一下 - 这是什么地方？
Why is this a toy store?
为什么这里是玩具店？
Now I know how dangerous it is
现在我知道这有多危险
If something goes wrong, you and me
如果出了问题，你和我
It ends awkwardly here
到这里就笨拙地结束了
I know
我知道
I saw and felt it yesterday
我昨天看到了并且感觉到了
I will go to school to avoid making mistakes
我会去学校以避免犯错误
Be sure to say the word
一定要说出这个词
I went because I had something to do
我去因为我有事要做
Because this is a dangerous situation
因为这是一个危险的情况
The lake has been prepared for a long time
湖已经准备了很长时间了
Get ready for the pool..Use words like this
准备好去泳池了..用这样的话
Be careful
当心
I know, I'm sorry, I'll be careful
我知道，对不起， 我会小心的
Because this is the first trip
因为这是第一次旅行
that's why
这就是为什么
The first person to travel through time. What were you doing in school?
第一个穿越时空的人 去学校做什么？
There must be a reason
这一定是有原因的
Do you think you don’t know enough?
你觉得你还不够了解吗？
A person who can travel freely through time and space
一个可以自由穿梭时空的人
Another time, I bought a house
还有一次，我买了房子
Pretend to be an ordinary teacher
假装自己是一名普通老师
Travel to and from the office as usual
像往常一样往返办公室
To and from the office
往返办公室
worst thing in life
生命中最糟糕的事情
Such a dangerous and dangerous lie
如此 危险又危险的谎言
enough to think
足以思考
It must be for important personal reasons
一定是因为重要的个人原因
But I don't ask why
但我不问 为什么
If you don’t have the confidence to speak up, don’t ask.
没有信心发声就 不要问
correct answer
正确答案
let's do what we have to do first
让我们先做我们必须做的事
Instead, let’s not encounter difficult situations like yesterday
相反， 我们不要像昨天那样遇到困难的情况
I will try
我会尝试
until we come back
直到我们回来
Because they are in the same boat
因为他们在同一条船上
I have to go to school
我得去学校了
Return to China after graduation
毕业后回国
Be as inconspicuous as possible
尽可能 不显眼
if it interferes with my case
如果它干扰我的案件
At that time, school was over
那时，学校已经放学了
This is true no matter what time
无论什么时间都是如此
I agree
我同意
But I don’t know if the detective yesterday will come again.
但不知道昨天侦探 会不会再来
i don't know how to speak
我不知道如何说话
Let's go first
我们先走吧
let's go
我们走吧
Yes Yes
是的是的
What are you afraid of?
你担心什么？
Don't worry
不用担心
It is also possible for young people to work part-time
年轻人打工 也是可以的
Come back quickly and buy a bottle of rice wine
快点回来买一瓶米酒
The only son was sent to a distant place
唯一的儿子被送到远方
Think of your lonely friend
想想你孤独的朋友
Cool, I know, hang up, Commander Gin.
酷，我知道，挂断电话， Gin 指挥官
(Principal Yoon Bong-koo)
（尹奉九校长）
sorry
对不起
My call is a bit long
我的电话有点长
Now
现在
I am really happy today
今天我很开心
This is my first time moving to a new school since school started
这是我开学以来 第一次搬到新学校
even two
甚至两个
This is also within one day
这也是在一天之内
There is another picture
还有一张图
- I don't wear it
- 我不穿
Although I briefly met him in a club not too long ago
虽然不久前 我在俱乐部里粗略地见过他
say goodbye officially
正式说再见
I am Mr. Yoon Hye-jun
我是尹惠俊先生
if you look carefully
如果你仔细观察
- Picture.. - I don't wear it
- 图片.. - 我不戴
Yes
是的
Anyway
反正
From today on, this is your nephew's class teacher.
从今天起，这边 就是你侄子的班主任了
Is the father the same person?
父亲是同一个人吗？
so me too
所以我也是
I need it
我需要它
Detective Badong is a very good detective
巴东侦探 是一个很好的侦探
Thanks to these children, our village
感谢这些孩子们，我们村
very safe
很安全
I have to think of it as gratitude
我必须将其视为感激之情
i absolutely need it
我绝对需要它
How could I meet such a nice person last night?
昨晚怎么会遇到这么好的人？
Oh, sorry, Chairman
哦，对不起，主席
No, I didn't know it was a member of our family
不， 我不知道这是我们家庭的成员
Because the head teacher and parents of students
因为班主任和学生家长
We are all part of the Wuzheng Middle School family
我们都是五正中学大家庭 的一员
Let's get comfortable, okay?
让我们舒服一点吧， 好吗？
second head
第二头
The first head is here too
第一个头也在这里
What a mystery
多么神秘啊
Uncle Yang, I see these two heads here
杨叔叔我在这里看到这两个头
as far as I know
据我所知
It seems you don't have a father either
看来你也没有父亲
not talking
不说话
What happened again?
又发生什么事了？
Even though he moved to a new school
尽管他搬到了新学校
If you come with distant relatives
如果你和远房亲戚一起来
The answer is obvious
答案是显而易见的
Even if there are still people who won’t come
即使还有不来的人
elementary, middle, and high school
小学、初中、 高中
Welcome ceremony graduation sports meeting
欢迎仪式毕业运动会
Such a person has never been here for a day
这样的人一天都没来过
After drinking, he started fighting with someone by the collar.
喝完酒后， 他开始和某人揪住衣领打架
Such a person has gone through all the important moments in my life
这样一个人，走过了我人生所有的重要时刻
My father is such a person
我的父亲就是这样一个人
Is there such a father?
有这样的父亲吗？
bamboo
竹子
It feels strange to hear these words from your mouth
从你嘴里听到这些话感觉 很奇怪
So what's the main thing?
那么主要的是什么？
preschool
学前班
School name must be Primary School
学校名称必须是 小学
So if you come here to support me
所以，如果你来这里支持我
Ekantasun E also...
埃坎塔孙E也..
hehe
呵呵
Did I tell you yesterday?
我昨天告诉过你了吗？
- Not interested - Wait a minute
- 不感兴趣 - 等一下
hehe
呵呵
I also said it yesterday
我昨天也说过了
Don't meddle in my business
别插手我的事
open my ears
放开我的耳朵
(teacher's office)
（教师办公室）
Not like distant relatives
不像是远房亲戚
Didn't I say it's cool?
我不是说很酷吗？
Yes, although I promise to keep it that way
是的，尽管我承诺会保持这种状态
- So cute - No, he's the coolest
- 太可爱了 - 不，他是最酷的
- Haha- He bought it
- 呵呵 - 他买了
- Hey, I don't have any pocket money. - Let me do it.
- 嘿，我没零花钱了 - 让我来做吧
- That's right - not these girls.
- 没错 - 不是这些女孩
- Hey, do you have any left? - No, give me one.
- 嘿，你还有剩下的吗？ - 没有，给我一个
(Employment Studies)
（就业研究）
- is that so? - Yes
- 是这样吗？ - 是的
bamboo
竹子
- Oh - Madam
- 哦 - 女士
- How are you ?
- 你还好吗 ？
Mother
母亲
hehe
呵呵
monitor
班长
goodbye
再见
- Hello
- 你好 你好
Come in
进来
(Five Flavors Award)
（五味奖）
This is the same lesson we started teaching today
这与今天 开始教授的课程相同
Pei Yunying
裴允英
I missed a little school because of housework
因为做家务我错过了一点学校
a little older than you
比你大一点
What does it have to do with old age?
与年老有什么关系？
If you are in the same class, you are all friends
如果你们在同一个班级， 你们都是朋友
- That's right - Yes
- 没错 - 是的
Cool, check it out yourself
酷，你自己检查一下
not yet
还没有
Geun Hye Kyung Lee Eun Ha Bayuri
根惠京 李恩河 巴尤里
You three, Ginglieburt, are barely moving.
你们三个，Ginglieburt， 几乎没有动弹
If you bully a new classmate, you will be punished
如果你欺负新同学， 你会受到惩罚
Yes
是的
The same goes for upper-class seniors
上流社会的前辈也一样
There is indeed no hope
确实没有希望了
Except our Mitsu
除了我们的三津
(Five Flavors Award)
（五味奖）
There's an empty seat there. Go sit down.
那里有空位， 你去坐吧
Yes
是的
That's it
就是这样了
- thanks, thanks
- 谢谢 谢谢
come over
过来
- Ha - Hey
- 哈 - 嘿
- Don't do this. - Really?
- 别这样做 - 真的吗？
- Are you kidding me? - Very good.
- 你在开玩笑吗 - 很好
- That's what I can do - Hey, the teacher is here
- 这就是我能做的 - 嘿，老师来了
- You - bring it back.
- 你 - 把它带回来
Quiet
安静
I have a seat
我有座位
Now there is a new student in our class
现在我们班来了 一位新学生
Feel free to say goodbye
随意说再见
This is Bashisu
这是巴希苏
What have you done?
做了什么？
Yes
是的
Said a lot
说了很多
Because it goes against the spirit of rock and roll
因为这违背了摇滚精神
- Okay - See?
- 好 - 看到了吗？
Excellent
出色地
Yes, that's how the pattern is set up
是的，图案就是这样设置的
What will happen if we go against the spirit?
如果违背灵的话会怎样呢？
sit where you like
坐在你喜欢的地方
That's it
就是这样
smoothly
顺利
- smoothly
- 顺利
How did it happen?
它是怎么发生的？
I think I should stay here a little longer
我想我应该在这里多呆一会儿
are you happy?
你快乐吗？
Do you like Virginia Wolfe?
你喜欢弗吉尼亚·沃尔夫吗？
Do you know this book?
你知道这本书吗？
"If you give her a hundred years."
“如果给她一百年。”
"Give her her own room."
“给她自己的房间。”
"If you give me 500 days a year"
“如果给我一年五百天”
"Let her speak her mind."
“让她说出自己的想法。”
“If only half of what I’m using now could be removed.”
“要是我现在用的东西能去掉一半就好了。”
"I concluded that I could write a better book. "
“我的结论是我可以写一本更好的书。 ”
"If you give me another hundred years, she will."
“如果你再给我一百年， 她会的。”
"I want to be a poet"
“我要成为一名诗人”
They are bathing the cat
他们正在给猫洗澡
(Employment Studies)
（就业研究）
I am very happy
我很高兴
(Commitment Letter of Diligence and Integrity)
（勤勉诚信承诺书）
bamboo
竹子
you can really play guitar
你真的可以弹吉他
Hear that?
听到？
Slater ranked fourth
斯莱特排名第四
Are you playing with electronic codes?
你玩的是电子码吗？
Bamboo fingers are also very fast and have a good sense of rhythm
竹手指也很快， 节奏感很好
I finally found my partner
我终于找到了我的伴侣
I am very happy
我很高兴
My name is Yu Bum
我的名字是Yu Bum
Aren't you crazy?
你不是疯了吗？
I am very happy
我很高兴
Said he was very happy
说他很幸福
I have to say something, don't I?
我必须说点什么，不是吗？
but in a decidedly childish way
但以一种明显幼稚的方式
Because they are all childish jokes
因为它们都是幼稚的玩笑
What will it be?
会是什么？
I don’t know if it’s a good use or not.
不知道用得好不好
- Already following - Yes
- 已关注 - 是
This Bakola
这个巴科拉
I am excited
我很兴奋
teacher
老师
I must speak for a while
我必须说一会儿
Where are you pretending to be kissing? Do you want to die?
哪里装亲了， 想死吗？
Because I don’t have time, I listen carefully
因为没有时间所以仔细听
Now the other person’s eyes
现在对方的眼神
look at this
看这个
almost
差不多
And then all of a sudden, what was that?
然后突然间， 那是什么？
Well, that's a nod.
嗯，那就是点头
Just then he sat down to pack his things
就在这时他坐下来收拾东西
raise your head like this
像这样抬起头
I had a nosebleed once...
有一次就流鼻血了..
Hey you won't do this again
嘿，你不会再这样了
Now that I think about it I'm doing this
现在想想我正在做这件事
I'll bow like this
我会像这样鞠躬
Is the head made of stone?
头是石头做的吗？
That's why you teach
这就是 你教书的原因
ha
哈
Our father taught us this
我们的父亲教我们这个
when i started preschool
当我开始上学前班时
If the first child you meet is aggressive
如果你遇到的第一个孩子有攻击性
I told him he did it to scare me
我告诉他这样做是为了吓唬我
Although my parents passed away when I graduated, I am no longer with them
虽然毕业时我的父母 去世了，但我已经不在了
Although I have never learned anything other than this
虽然除了这个我没学过
but because it's still useful
但因为它仍然有用
Dads want to teach techniques like this
爸爸们想教这样的技巧
that's why
这就是为什么
Does your father want to run away?
你父亲想逃跑吗？
There must be a reason
一定是有原因的
- You know what - Yeah
- 你知道吗 - 嗯
A 19-year-old boy is teaching children
一名19岁的少年正在教孩子们
There's no need for that
没有必要那样
ha
哈
How are you?
你还好吗？
- My nose is bleeding. - Ha.
- 我的鼻子流血了 - 哈
Are you crazy?
你疯了？
Please be quiet
请安静
I can't concentrate anymore
我无法再集中注意力
I think that's enough
我认为这就足够了
ha
哈
Prince No. 52 is here
五二皇子来了
What
什么
- Attention - Sit down
- 注意 - 坐下
fish
鱼
Four
四
- What happened? - Shu
- 发生什么事了？ - 舒
Now I have to enjoy this moment as much as possible
现在我必须尽可能地享受这一刻
three
三
Year
年
one
一
What were you told to do after graduation?
毕业后你被告知要做什么？
- I have to go home
- 我必须回家
Yes, I have to go back and do my homework.
是的，我得回去做作业了
Don't go out after ten o'clock in the evening
晚上十点以后不要出门
I can't go to the reading room because I have to go to work
我不能去阅览室，因为我要去工作
Studying at home this time
这次在家学习
If you can't concentrate, sleep like this
如果你无法集中注意力，就这样睡觉
Sleep is the best medicine
睡眠是最好的良药
Don’t go to the mountains or riverside during the day
白天不要去山上、河边
Don't go to the dentist
不要去看牙医
Don't go to dark places
不要去黑暗的地方
Don't trust anyone easily
不要轻易相信任何人
The bad guy comes with a smile
坏人微笑着来了
Currently, my school friends
目前，我学校的朋友
think about it
想想看
Wait three or four months until you are 20
等三四个月，直到20岁
I'm free from now on
从此我就自由了
- So... - Let's study this time, teacher.
- 那么.. - 这次学习吧，老师
open book
打开书本
before that rant
在那句咆哮之前
just a fish
只是一条鱼
The five-second prince because he is the five-second prince
五秒王子因为他是 五秒王子
Nickname of Prince Wuer
五二皇子的昵称
Unless you don't listen, do you have to listen every time?
除非不听，否则 每次都要听吗？
so terrible
太糟糕了
don't just say too much
不要只说太多
It is also known as Dom Prince
它也被称为 Dom 王子
don't tell me
别告诉我
So why does every name have to include prince?
那么为什么每个名字都要 加上王子呢？
How could I not add it?
我怎么可以不添加呢？
To write Yunbe Ochunga
为了写 Yunbe Ochunga
Learn how to use it
了解如何使用它
Features that are different from Yoongi Ochunga
与玧其Ochunga不同的特点
the form described
所描述的形式
must understand
必须明白
Now first
现在先
Let’s talk about Yunbi Ochung’s net worth
我们来谈谈Yunbi Ochung的身价
as i said yesterday
正如我昨天所说
First written in our words by Yonbe Ochunga
首先由 Yonbe Ochunga 用我们的话写成
a long poem
一首长诗
Because it is reflected in music and literature
因为它体现在音乐和文学方面
Korean literature is valuable
韩国文学有价值
This work is from the late Goryeo Dynasty
这部作品是高丽时代后期的作品
In studying the early Korean language
在研究朝鲜早期语言时
Has historical value..
具有历史记录的价值..
- Hello sir
- 你好先生
Mom...Grandpa hates me
妈妈..爷爷讨厌我
I hate people who fight too
我也讨厌打架的人
I said so much because I am calm
我说了这么多是因为我很平静
I've been losing UFC fights since day one
从第一天起 我就一直输掉 UFC 比赛
Let’s do our own thing and don’t criticize each other
我们做好自己的事， 不要互相批评
that's what i said
这就是我所说的
Don’t look too closely during class
上课时不要看得太紧
You can't go anywhere after graduation.
毕业了就哪儿也去不了
Stay in the classroom because I'm going to call you
呆在教室里 ，因为我会打电话给你
- Teacher - Yes
- 老师 - 是的
go where you have to go
去你必须去的地方
Wow
哇
Do you talk very intimately?
你们说话很亲密吗？
Thank you so much
非常感谢
Thank you for your compliments on your homework
谢谢你对写作业的夸奖
I say well written because it is well written
我说写得好是因为写得好
It's not a matter of gratitude
这不是感恩的问题
This time I was a little shy to show it
这次我有点害羞地表现出来
In fact, I later
其实我后来
Do you think you could be a novelist?
你认为你可以成为一名小说家吗？
certainly
当然
Even if it takes too long, it will take too long
即使需要太长的时间，也会花费太长的时间
I don’t know if it will be very popular.
不知道会不会很受欢迎
so work hard
所以努力工作
Do you know Jimmy Zu?
你知道吉米祖吗？
This is a best-selling author
这是一位畅销书作家
(academic points)
（学术点）
Not in the bathroom either
洗手间里也没有
Where will it go?
它会去哪里？
Did you bring it?
你带来了吗？
Excellent
出色地
I fixed some existing sentences
我修正了一些现有的句子
The content is also fixed
内容也 固定了
You are already tired from doing homework
你已经因为写作业而累了
but
但
Almost all the lines I wrote were deleted
我写的几乎所有行都 被删除了
Oh, that's it
噢，就是这样
It doesn't matter
没关系
Because that will be a good result
因为那将会是一个好的结果
Anyway, I wrote the original work
反正原作是我写的
The thing is, anyone can do it
问题是，任何人都可以做到
Isn't it?
不是吗？
Well, yes, of course
嗯，是的，当然
So come out quickly
所以快点出来吧
Excellent
出色地
Because good results come from your hands
因为好的结果是出自你的双手
I have no general complaints
我没有一般性的抱怨
Corrected
已更正
anyone can do it
任何人都可以做到
(Storage Room)
（储存室）
(Always pay attention to fire prevention)
（时刻注意防火）
I've always done this
我一直都是这样做的
I wonder if it's the same for you
我想知道 你是否也一样
Can you write without help ?
你能在没有别人帮助的情况下 写作吗？
Although I have watched it for six years
虽然我已经看了六年了
Even if it’s just a little homework
哪怕只是写一点作业
I'm surprised others hired and got it done
我很惊讶其他人雇用并完成了它
If you really think anyone can do it
如果你真的认为任何人都能做到
Why do you have to do it yourself?
为什么你必须自己做？
Leverage other people's skills
利用他人的技能
Are you that bald?
你有这么秃吗？
No, not bald
不，不是秃头
I think it's embarrassing
我认为这很尴尬
Hiding in this place?
躲在这个地方？
Such a thing
这样的事情
At least here, it can't be a secret
至少在这里， 这不能成为秘密
Let's go to the teacher's office
我们去老师办公室吧
Misu, are you okay?
米苏你还好吗？
this..
这..
I want to do it
我要做
Class is about to start, come on
快上课了，快来吧
Let's go to Mizu
我们去美津吧
how to really do it
如何真正做到
Why can't my mother move like this?
为什么我妈妈就不能这样动呢？
There must be something there
那里肯定有东西
This is the first face I've ever seen
这是我见过的第一张脸
A room in the upper class?
高年级的一个房间？
Is Lee Sun-el in your room?
Lee Sun-el是你房间里的吗？
Sun El Sun El Why?
孙埃尔 孙埃尔 为什么？
he..
他..
Can you give me this?
你能给我这个吗？
I trust you
我相信你
Now you know how fishy this is
现在你知道这有多可疑了
Go to the corridor where the girls' classroom is
到女生教室所在的走廊
Don’t you know not to cut it?
不知道不要剪吗？
Are school rules a joke?
校规是个笑话吗？
no i'm sorry
不，我很抱歉
- Please forgive me once - Come on
- 请原谅我一次 - 你来
(Copyrighted invention)
（拥有版权发明）
(Let us move forward with wisdom)
（让我们用智慧继续前行）
- Did you come back? - Tarta
- 你回来了吗？ - 塔尔塔
If Wumisu is really as far away as the novels written by my mother
如果五米须真的有我妈妈写的小说那么 远
Today's question is just the beginning
今天的问题只是一个开始
I can't even sleep because it makes me feel so uncomfortable
我什至无法入睡，因为这样做让我感到很不舒服
(Let us give up ourselves and love each other)
（让我们放弃自己， 彼此相爱）
Why is it taking so long?
为什么要花这么长时间？
don't go anywhere and wait
不要去任何地方并等待
Be careful
当心
What
什么
Yun Yang, be careful
云扬小心点
Do you really want to go to this place?
你真的想去这个地方吗？
The principal said today's dinner was really...
校长说今天的晚餐真是..
Even if it rains, the earth will split in two
就算下雨，大地裂成两半
I was told I had to attend
我被告知我必须参加
I've been talking a lot since before
从以前开始我就一直 说很多话
so?
所以？
How much do you know about the principal who has just been here a month?
你对刚来一个月的 校长了解多少？
so
所以
Why would the principal fall in love with such a person?
为什么校长 会爱上这样一个人？
Sorry, I'm late
对不起，来晚了
No?
不？
What
什么
Are you not as smart as I thought?
你是不是没有我想象的那么聪明？
being threatened
受到威胁
Horrible people to work with
可怕的人工作
that warning
那个警告
Until now, I don’t know how Shan’e was restrained, but I listened carefully
到现在为止， 我不知道善娥是如何被克制的，但我仔细地听着
What you have done so far
到目前为止你已经做到了
All the cowardly things he did to get ahead
他为了出人头地而做出的 所有懦弱行为
It won't be what you want anymore
不会再如你所愿
I will stop everything no matter what
无论如何我都会停止一切
Yes
是的
Misu
米苏
Where are you going?
你到底要去哪里？
A chapter from the senior year to the freshmen
高年级的一章 对新生说
Let's see what we do here
让我们看看我们在这里做什么
Mom told me to come back early
妈妈叫我早点回来
I have a place where I can go in for a while, but I’m going back today
我有地方可以进去一会儿， 不过今天先回去了
He Wuguang
何五光
Do you think my sister ran away like this?
你以为我妹妹就这样逃跑了？
No eavesdropping allowed
不许偷听
When the windows are opened due to cloudy weather
由于阴天而打开窗户时
So even if it hurts
所以，即使很痛
I don't know anything about Mitsu's method
我对Mitsu的方法一无所知
if you want to fight
如果你想战斗
Shouldn't you be sure of the other person's situation ?
难道你不应该确定对方的情况 吗？
Which way do you want to go?
你要走哪条路？
Then give it to new classmates
然后给新同学
I want to write a message
我要写一条短信
Hey, do you have a girlfriend?
嘿，你有女朋友吗？
Hey, people change all the time, you know?
嘿，人随时都会改变， 你知道吗？
if i see a beautiful girl
如果我看到一个美丽的女孩
Brave girlfriend first...
勇敢的女朋友先..
I just gave
我刚刚给了
I tried it first
我先尝试了一下
A guy who can't even lift weights
一个连举重 都不会的家伙
I just need to ask for the phone number
我只需要询问电话号码
It would be fine if the head teacher didn't stop me
如果班主任不阻止我就好了
Well
唔
I'll go find the head teacher tomorrow
明天我去找班主任
- cool guy
- 很酷的 家伙
"What's your home phone number?"
“你家里的电话号码是多少？”
Yes 53 2355
是 53 2355
What 53 2355
什么 53 2355
i heard somewhere
我在某处听到过
Hey, isn't this the head teacher's phone number?
哎， 这不是班主任的电话吗？
Well, our new student
嗯，我们家的 那个新学生
If you remember, give me a call and I'll take care of it
如果你记得的话，给我打电话，我会处理的
Come back soon
快回来
(Let's use it as a private toilet)
（我们把它用作私人厕所吧）
How to do it?
怎么做？
I don't think so, but it won't be an umbrella
我不这么认为，但它 不会是一把雨伞
As a student, can I say whatever I want?
作为一个学生，我能随便说吗？
I am 22 years old
我22岁
oh yes
噢，是的
So, what does this word mean?
那么，这个词是什么意思呢？
I know very little about the Five Lights Dharma
我对五光法 知之甚少
I said I was threatened
我说我被威胁了
If you really feel this way
如果你真的有这样的感觉
Probably not a real threat
很可能不是真正的威胁
This is a casual test
这是一个随意的测试
Is this a test?
这是一个测试吗？
Is there such a thing?
有这样的事吗？
Which button does it respond to when pressed?
按下时它会响应哪个按钮？
What are the disadvantages?
缺点是什么？
Is there something as useful as a secret card?
有没有像秘密卡这样有用的东西？
Mizu didn't attack at all until she fully understood this
直到她完全明白这一点之前， 美津根本没有攻击
but if you know
但如果你知道
it's over
结束了
threaten..
威胁..
Horrible people to work with
可怕的人工作
Yes
是的
Be careful
当心
What
什么
Yun Yang, be careful
云扬小心点
as a sister
作为姐姐
You said this when you first met me
你第一次见到我就说出这样的话
looks dangerous
看起来很危险
When you look at a goal and move forward
当你看着一个目标并 向前迈进时
This is a common trap
这是常见的陷阱
How are you?
你还好吗？
That's why you have to be careful
这就是为什么你必须小心
let's get into consciousness
让我们进入意识
drink slowly
慢慢喝
this is gonna be really crazy
这真的会很疯狂
Don't look at it like that
别这样看
This is not a dangerous place in our house.
我们家这 不是危险的地方
It's just that the method is wrong
只是方法错了
This is not ordinary
这不是一般的
Let's have a drink and enjoy
让我们一起喝一杯，尽情享受
I like you
我喜欢你
Do you know this, Wu Guang?
你知道这个吗，五光？
I can't say, but I can know
我不能说，但我可以知道
Maybe you just pretend not to know
也许你只是假装不知道
This means it's not the first time
这意味着这不是第一次
It means it will be fine soon
意味着很快就会好的
Mother
母亲
This is a sad picture
这是一幅悲伤的画面
will be very convenient
会很方便
Who are you looking for?
来找谁..
This guy
这家伙
How are you?
你还好吗？
Come
来
Did you tell me to trust you ?
你有告诉我要相信你 吗？
please
请
not really
并不真地
I am strong
我很强
Please trust me
请相信我
Then let's meet in Wuzhengli
那么我们在五正里见面吧
Because I'll tell you what it means
因为我会告诉你这意味着什么
keep living and hold on
继续生活并坚持下去
I'm afraid he won't come
我怕他不会来
I'm still worried that I won't be able to come
我还是担心我来不了
listen carefully
仔细听
From now on your life will be absolute hell
从现在开始，你的生活将是绝对的地狱
I never took my eyes off you for a moment
我一刻也 没有把目光从你身上移开
Because I will watch until the end
因为我会一直看到最后
If you have debt to pay
如果您有债务需要偿还
no matter what
不管是什么
I'll make sure you don't miss a single payment
我会让你一个也不漏付
That's why it must be really good
这就是为什么 它一定非常好
Prisoner number 4013
囚犯编号4013
Wuminsu
五民苏
Who are you?
你是谁？
a little hair
一点头发
How did you know I'd be there?
你怎么知道我会在那里？
Because I think it's my turn
因为我认为轮到我了
List of main suspects at the time
当时主要嫌疑人名单
There are three people including you.
包括你在内一共三人
(1987 murder suspect Ba Xixiu)
（1987年谋杀案 嫌疑人巴熙秀）
The murder that will happen in three days
三天后将 发生的谋杀案
The first suspect is Pakistan
第一个嫌疑人是巴基斯
The second suspect is Yu Bum Yong
第二名嫌疑人是Yu Bum Yong
(Bom Bom Theater)
（Bom Bom 剧场）
(Judaism)
（犹太教）
A third suspect has been identified as the culprit
第三名嫌疑人 已被确定为罪魁祸首
Thirty years in prison
入狱三十年
Wuminsu
五民苏
(Wu Minsu)
（五民苏）
Isn't that the person you met today?
那不是你今天遇到的人吗？
(Bom Bom Theater)
（Bom Bom 剧场）
Who are you?
你是谁？
Why are you really here?
你为什么真的在这里？
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》
Two days before the first case appeared
第一个病例出现前两天
one of the suspects
其中一名嫌疑人
He has been arrested at the police station
他已在警察局被捕
The other two are still inconspicuous
另外两个依然 不起眼
Everything was covered in fog then
那时一切都被雾气笼罩
She is coming
她来了
she is the first victim
她是第一个受害者
that person..
那个人..
i know something
我知道一些事情
If you don't know what happens here
如果你不知道这里会发生什么
must be informed
必须告知
Because we don't know what will happen in the future
因为我们不知道未来会发生什么
(appendix)
（附录）
"A Stranger I Met"
《我遇见的一个陌生人》